

Michael Horvath

Data Scientist

michaelhorvath87@gmail.com



949-409-5713



www.michaelhorvathdataguy.com

About me -

Originally from Kansas, Michael has lived in eight states and two countries. Michael enjoys climbing, running, playing guitar and anything that gets him outside. He's been writing software for about seven years now, but he's been exploring since the day he could walk perhaps even earlier.

Skill

Python

Business Intelligence

VIM

Linux

Data Analysis

Productionizing Models

Figuring It Out

Teamplayer ** 6 Easygoing ** 4.78

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

beliefs

Passion is a must.

Software = Poetry + Math

education

2006-2011 B.A. cum laude University of Kansas

Statistics and Research Methods

2002-2006 High school, 4.0 GPA Shawnee Mission East HS

Extras: Diving, Soccer, Choir, Science Olympics

awards

1997-2001 Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools

2005 Science Olympiad State Champion, Chemistry

2006 CalTech Signature Award, Excellence in Science and Mathematics

2016 Heart and Soul Award, Lawrence Ultimate Frisbee League

experience

2022 - 2023 Software Engineer

Maxar Technologies

- Back-end development in Sanic micro-service architecture system.

2021 - 2022 Lead Data Scientist Fluxergy

- Head of data and algorithms department.

- Study design, program evaluation, data sampling, and data analysis.

- Collaborated cross-departmentally to design, connect, and commodify business intelligence pipelines.

- Oversaw algorithm development and increased accessibility of data for decision making, via KPI dashboards and PowerBI reports.

2020 - 2021 Algorithms Engineer

- Developed primary image-based PCR analysis algorithm from prototype to ISO certificied embedded product.

- Deploy classification algorithms and optimize for wide array of inputs.

2018 - 2020 Software Engineer

- Designed, developed, and maintained data-centric internal applications.

- Work across departments to gather requirements and build out specifactions for first three versions of company-wide data infrastructure.

2017 - 2018 Machine Learning Engineer Embrace Healthwear

- Model selection, data preprocessing and vectorization for machine learning classification of high-frequency time-series data.

2015 - 2022 Personal Projects

> - Neural net generator for exploring node generation, tuning and lifecycle of basic machine learning processes in Elixir.

- Machine learning-based high frequency trading bot.

tools

2017-2023 Python, Scikit-Learn, SciPy, Pandas, Numpy, TensorFlow, Matplotlib,

> MySQL, Docker, docker-compose, Git, Cloud resources (Azure and AWS), database design, datalake, scaling and paralelization, Elasticsearch and Kibana, PowerBI, CI/CD, machine learning, support vector machines, knearest neighbors, natural language processing, computer vision, lambda

Program evaluation, technical liaison, public speaking, regression analysis, 2010-2020

ANOVA, MANOVA, optimization, structural equation modeling, business

intelligence